Emil Leon Post Papers 1888-1995 Mss.Ms.Coll.45
American Philosophical Society
Emil Leon Post Papers
1927-1991
Mss.Ms.Coll.45
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Linear feet
A Polish-born mathematician who worked in symbolic logic, set theory and computation theory, Emil Leon Post received his doctorate from Columbia in 1920 for a dissertation proving the consistency of the propositional calculus described in Whitehead and Russell's Principia mathematica. He joined the faculty at City College of the City University of New York in 1932, where he remained until his death in 1954. Although illness continually interrupted Post's career, he made important contributions to the concepts of completeness and consistency and to recursive functions, foundational to modern computing theory. In 1936, he introduced the concept of a "Post machine," a sort of precursor to the von Neumann's notion of a program. The Post Papers consist of 8 linear feet of professional correspondence, research notes, and papers, to which have been added a small number of items of biographical interest.
Post, Emil Leon, 1897-1954
Bibliography
Emil Post, Solvability, Provability, Definability: the Collected Works of Emil L. Post Boston: Birkhäuser, 1994 Call no.: 510 P84s.
Separated Materials note
All photographs have been removed from Series I-V and placed in Series VI, with cross-references added in the original series. Reprints have been moved to the Printed Materials Department of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Post notebooks were donated by Martin Davis in 1986 (Accession 1986-332ms). The remaining Post Papers were donated to the APS by Phyllis Post Goodman in 1992 (Accession 1992-1345ms and 1992-1088ms) and 1994 (Accession 1994-99ms, 1994-367ms, and 1994-238ms). It is expected that further additions may be made to this collection.
Arrangement note
Each series is arranged alphabetically by folder title and then chronologically within each folder.
Scope and Contents note
The Emil Leon Post Papers (1888-1995) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Post, research notes by Post, materials gathered by Post's daughter, Phyllis Post Goodman, and photographs, which document Post's career as a mathematician.
The papers (8 boxes; 4 linear feet) are divided into six series:
Series I. Correspondence, 1912-1955 (2 boxes; 0.75 linear feet)
Series II. Subject Files, 1888-1955 (1 box; 6 folders)
Series III. Works by Post, 1921-1953 (2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet)
Series IV. Research Notes, 1917-1953 (6 boxes; 2.75 linear feet)
Series V. Materials Gathered by Phyllis Post Goodman, 1955-1995 (1 box; 0.25 linear feet)
Series VI. Photographs, 1924, 1948 (1 box, 3 folders)
Biographical/Historical note
Emil L. Post was born in Poland in 1897. At the age of seven he emigrated with his mother and sisters to New York, where his father worked in the successful family clothing and fur business.
As a child growing up in Harlem, Post was especially interested in astronomy. Tragically, before age thirteen he lost his left arm in an accident. Post wrote to several observatories asking whether his handicap would exclude him from the profession of astronomy. While the response from Harvard College Observatory was encouraging ("there is no reason why you may not become eminent in astronomy"), the superintendent of the U.S. Naval Observatory wrote that "in my opinion the loss of your left arm would be a very serious handicap to your becoming a professional astronomer. In observational work with instruments the use of both hands is necessary in all the work of this observatory." Discouraged, Post turned his intellect away from the heavens and toward mathematics.
After graduating from Townsend Harris High School, Post entered City College of New York. By the time he received a B.S. in mathematics in 1917, Post had already done much of the work for a paper on generalized differentiation that was eventually published in 1930. From 1917-1920 Post was a graduate student at Columbia University. His doctoral dissertation involved the mathematical study of systems of logic, specifically the application of the truth table method to the propositional calculus of Whitehead and Russell's Principia Mathematica. Post was able to show that the axioms of propositional calculus were both complete and consistent with respect to the truth table method. This dissertation was to help form the foundation of modern proof theory.
Post spent the 1920-1921 academic year at Princeton on a post-doctoral fellowship. It was during this period that he continued to analyze the Principia Mathematica and began to grapple with a revolutionary idea that would become famous in the 1930s: the fundamental incompleteness of any formal logic. Unfortunately for Post, his early formulations were fragmentary and as he struggled to work them out, Kurt Gödel, who had no knowledge of Post's work, announced his landmark "incompleteness theorem" in 1931. When Alonzo Church published "An Unsolvable Problem of Elementary Number Theory" in 1936, Post's work, which remained unpublished, lost its claim to originality. In a 1938 letter to Gödel, a disappointed but gracious Post remarked that "any resentment I may have is at the Fates if not myself.... I have the greatest admiration for your work, and after all it is not ideas but the execution of ideas that constitute a mark of greatness."
In 1921 Post suffered his first attack of manic-depressive illness, a condition which was to reoccur throughout his life, often at the peak of creative periods. He recovered from this first occurrence well enough to begin teaching at Cornell, but after another collapse he found himself unemployed and unwanted in academia. For years he survived by teaching high school in New York. In 1932, Post began teaching at City College of New York, where he stayed for the rest of his career. Despite a treatment regimen that limited research time and a teaching load of sixteen hours per week, he continued to produce important papers.
In 1936 Post contributed a paper to the first issue of the Journal of Symbolic Logic entitled "Finite Combinatory Processes--Formulation I." This paper had much in common with Alan Turing's work on a universal computing machine. While Turing's work described the mechanics of such a machine, Post focused on the instructions, or "software," that would make the machine work. Post was able to prove that all computational processes could be reduced to a set of instructions that manipulated two symbols, "0" and "1."
Post's most influential mathematical work arose out of an address given to the American Mathematical Society in 1943. His paper on recursively enumerable sets, published in 1944, spawned a series of investigations on completeness and simplicity in set theory.
As a teacher at City College during the 1930s and 1940s, Post had a reputation as a demanding yet fair instructor. His classes were organized to the minute, and he did not encourage questions from his students. Still, he was a popular teacher who had many students go on to become professional mathematicians.
Post continued to struggle with manic depression throughout his career. In 1954, after a period of fairly good health, he became ill for the last time. He died of a heart attack shortly after being treated with electro-shock therapy in an upstate New York hospital. He was survived by his wife, Gertrude Singer Post (1900-1956) and his daughter, Phyllis Post Goodman.
American Mathematical Society.; Church, Alonzo, 1903-; City University of New York. City College; Davis, Martin, 1928-; Godel, Kurt; Quine, W. V., (Willard Van Orman); Algorithms; Drawings.; Eugenics--United States; Journals (notebooks); Logic, Symbolic and mathematical; Set theory
- Series I. Correspondence, 1912-1955; 2 boxes; 0.75 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence from City College colleagues, former students, and academic institutions. Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter. The series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder. There are a few handwritten postcards from Post to Martin Davis, as well as handwritten recommendations for others. The bulk of the correspondence, however, is from other people, including several letters from leading figures in the field of mathematics such as Kurt Gödel and Alonzo Church. Most of the correspondence deals with mathematics and recommendations; however, there are a few letters from government officials (including someone from the office of President Eisenhower) in response to Post's suggestions on various aspects of world events.
  Correspondents in Series I include:
  Church, Alonzo
  Davis, Martin
  Gödel, Kurt
  Quine, Willard
  - Abrahams, Albert P., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Air Warden Service, 1942 (Box 1)
  - American Journal of Mathematics, 1941-1942 (Box 1)
    Weyl, Hermann
  - The American Mathematical Monthly, 1952 (Box 1)
  - American Mathematical Society, 1943, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Annals of Mathematics, 1940-1941, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Aumann, John, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Bachiller, T.R., 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    In French
  - Barany, Ronald, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Beatty, S., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Berkowitz, J., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bernays, Paul, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Bishop, Kenneth, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Black, Max, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Blan, Julian, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Boone, William, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Bricker, Jacob Leon, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Brooklyn College, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Cecil, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Burroughs Adding Machine Company. Research Division, 1952-1953 (Box 1)
  - Bushey, Hobart, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Carmichael, R.D., 1952 (Box 1)
  - Chern, Bernard, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Church, Alonzo, 1927-1954 (Box 1)
    See Also Ser.I, The Journal of Symbolic Logic
  - City College, New York, 1941-1953 (Box 1)
  - City Club of New York, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Columbia University, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Craig, Homer, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Craig, William, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Davis, H.J., 1931 (Box 1)
  - Davis, Martin, 1948-1952 (Box 1)
  - Dean, Richard, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Dekker, J.C.E., 1949, 1952 (Box 1)
  - DeMendonca, Simao Carneiro, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, Jesse, 1940-1948 (Box 1)
  - Durrels, Julius, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Ehunprcis, Leon, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Office Of), 1952 (Box 1)
  - Elgop, Calvin, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Engel, Joseph H., n.d. (Box 1)
  - Engelman, Carl, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Faulk, David H., 1944 (Box 1)
  - Feeney, Walter J., 1952 (Box 1)
  - Finkel, William L., 1949 (Box 1)
  - Fischer, Irwin, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Fitch, Frederic, 1948-1953 (Box 1)
  - Forndon, Wilfred A., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Frankel, Abraham, 1949, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Freilich, Gerald, 1946, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Gill, Bennington, 1937, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Ginsburg, Jekuthial, 1937, 1940, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Gödel, Kurt, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - Gonseth, F., 1939, 1950 (Box 1)
    Some in French
  - Gottschall, Morton, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Grafton, Samuel, 1945-1948 (Box 1)
  - Gugino, E., 1952 (Box 1)
  - Gutterman, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Harvard College Observatory, 1912 (Box 1)
  - Henricksen, Melvin, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Himwich, A.A., 1929 (Box 1)
  - Hinshaw, Virgil, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Hochfeld, Emmanuel, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Iseki, Kiyosi, 1940, 1944, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Javits, Jacob, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Edgar, 1949 (Box 1)
  - The Journal of Symbolic Logic, 1938, 1942, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Kasner, Edward, 1940, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Kates, Robert, 1951, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Kelley, Thomas W., 1951 (Box 1)
  - Keyser, C.J., 1930, 1940, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Kingdon, Frank, 1946-1950, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Kleene, S.C., 1936-1954 (Box 1)
  - Kline, J.R., 1946 (Box 1)
  - Korngold, Eric, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Lerner, Max, 1947, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Lewis, C.I., 1940, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Linial, Samuel, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Littauer, Sebastian, 1928-1931, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Lorch, Lee, 1949-1951, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Lubell, Albert, 1937 (Box 1)
  - MacLane, Saunders, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
    See Also Ser.I, Bulletin of the American Mathematical Society
  - McLaughlin, Doris, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Martin, Norman M., 1948 (Box 1)
  - Mathematical Reviews, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Menger, Karl, 1931, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Mischel, Theodore, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Mostowski, Andrzej, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Myrick, Jack A., 1952 (Box 1)
  - Myhill, John, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Neuwirth, Jerome H., 1952 (Box 1)
  - New York Post, 1946 (Box 1)
  - New York University, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Newman, Donald J., 1948-1952 (Box 1)
  - Orleans, Joseph B., 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - Paley, Thomas, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Pincherle, S., 1930 (Box 1)
  - Pollack, Richard, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Quine, Willard V., 1937, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Reynolds, Frederick G., 1937-1944 (Box 2)
  - Rich, Barnett, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Moses, 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Ritt, J.F., 1931-1948 (Box 2)
  - Robbins, Leon C., 1951 (Box 2)
  - Rosenblatt, Murray, 1946, 1950, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Rosser, J. Barkley, 1953, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Rubel, Lee A., 1950 (Box 2)
  - Ruderman, Harry D., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Saurel, Paul, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Scholz, Heinrich, 1941-1948 (Box 2)
  - Schwartz, Jacob, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Shapiro, Harold N., 1943-1949 (Box 2)
  - Sheridan, Peter, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Shugar, Alvin C., n.d. (Box 2)
  - Silverman, Abe, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Simpson, Kenneth C., 1943 (Box 2)
  - Skolem, Th., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Solomon, Charles, 1930, 1932, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Sonkin, Si, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Stephens, Eugene, 1924, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Syracuse University, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Tarski, Alfred, 1940-1948 (Box 2)
  - Thompson, Dorothy, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
  - Turquette, A.R., 1942 (Box 2)
  - Unidentified, 1947, 1951, n.d. (Box 2)
  - The United Nations, 1945 (Box 2)
  - United States Naval Observatory, 1912 (Box 2)
  - United States. Secretary of State, 1951 (Box 2)
  - United States. War Department, 1948 (Box 2)
  - United States. White House, 1951, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Vandiver, H.S., 1953 (Box 2)
  - Webb, Donald L., 1935-1938 (Box 2)
  - Weinstein, Philip K., 1939 (Box 2)
  - Weisner, Louis, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Weissblum, Walter, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Wernick, William, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Weyl, Hermann, 1944 (Box 2)
    See Also Ser.I, American Journal of Mathematics
  - Widder, Dave V., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Wiener, Norbert, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Wirth, Herbert P., 1937-1943 (Box 2)
  - Winter, Jacob, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Wisan, Harold, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Wohl, Sonia, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Wouk, Arthur, n.d. (Box 2)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1888-1955; 1 box; 6 folders
  Includes appointments and awards, a biliography of Post's works, family history, an unidentified mailing list, letters of condolence on Post's death, and materials about teaching. The folders are arranged alphabetically by title. The earliest materials in this series are photocopies of family documents.
  - Appointments and Awards, 1941, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Bibliography, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Condolence Letters to Mrs. Post, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Family History, 1888-1954, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Mailing List, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Teaching Miscellanea, 1942-1953, n.d. (Box 2)
- Series III. Works by Post, 1921-1953; 2 boxes; 0.25 linear feet
  Original typed drafts of several of Post's papers on logic. This series also includes an annotated draft of Post's "Absolutely Unsolvable Problems." Also included are galley prints and notes for published papers.
  - "Absolutely Unsolvable Problems", n.d.; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Calculus of Variation, n.d. (Box 2)
  - [Combinations], 1935 (Box 2)
  - "Degrees of Recursive Unsolvability", 1948-1952 (Box 2)
  - "Finite Combinatory Processes--Formulation I", n.d. (Box 2)
  - "Formal Reductors of the General Combinatorial Decision Problem--Page Proofs", 1942 (Box 2)
  - "Formal Reductions of the General Combinatorial Decision Problem--Typescript", n.d. (Box 2)
  - "A Fundamental Problem in Postulate Theory" (Box 2)
    -See Ser.III, [Postulate Theory]
  - "The Generalized Derivative", n.d. (Box 2)
  - "Generalized Differentiation", 1929 (Box 2)
  - [Laplace Transform and Generalized Differention], 1923, 1932 (Box 2)
  - [Logic and Set Theory] (Box 2)
    - Folder #1, 1940-1949, n.d. (Box 2)
      On index cards
    - Folder #2, 1935, 1952 (Box 2)
  - "The Modern Paradoxes" (Box 2)
    -See Ser.III, [Logic and Set Theory]
  - "New Ideas for Researches" (Box 2)
  - "Note on Functions Identically Equal to Their Variations" (Box 2)
    -See Ser.III, [Calculus of Variation]
  - "Note on the Five Regular Polyhedra" (Box 2)
    -See Ser.III, [Five Regular Polyhedra]
  - "On Arthur Schath's "Proof" of a Form of the Cont. Hyp." (Box 2)
  - "Polyadic Groups"--Proof (Corrected), 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Polyadic Groups"--Typescript, 1935 (Box 3)
  - [Postulate Theory], 1921, 1935 (Box 3)
  - "Recursively Renumerable Sets of Positive Integers and Their Decision Problems"--Page Proofs (Box 3)
  - Recursively Renumerable Sets of Positive Integers and Their Decision Problems"--Typescript (Box 3)
  - "A Trifle"--Poem, 1922 (Box 3)
  - "A Variant of a Recursively Unsolvable Problem"--Page Proofs, n.d. (Box 3)
  - "A Variant of a Recursively Unsolvable Problem"--Typescript, n.d. (Box 3)
- Series IV. Research Notes, 1917-1953; 6 boxes; 2.75 linear feet
  Post's notebooks concerning various aspects of mathematical research, beginning with a notebook from 1917. The notebooks serve as a mathematical diary that covers Post's life as a mathematician.
  - "Calculus of Finite Processes", 1944 (Box 3)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. II-XVII
  - "Closed Truth Systems" Vol. I, 1929-1930 (Box 3)
  - "Closed Truth Systems" Vol. II, 1930 (Box 3)
  - "Closed Truth Systems" Vol. III, 1930-1931 (Box 3)
  - "Closed Truth Systems" Vol. IV, 1931-1932 (Box 4)
  - "Closed Truth Systems" Vol. V, 1931 (Box 4)
  - "Complete Equivalence of Normal Set and Recursive Function Development", 1942-1945 (Box 4)
  - [Corrections of Unknown Manuscript], n.d. (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. I, 1938 (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. II, 1938 (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. III, 1939 (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. IV, 1939 (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. V, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. VI, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. VII, 1942-1945 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. VIII, 1945 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. IX, 1945 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. X, 1945 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XI, 1945-1946 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XII, 1946 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XIII, 1946 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XIV, 1947 (Box 5)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XV, 1947 (Box 6)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XVI, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XVII, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - "Creative Logic" Vol. XVIII, 1949-1952 (Box 6)
  - "Definability" Vol. I, 1952 (Box 6)
  - "Definability" Vol. II, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - "The Logic of Mathematics" (Box 6)
    -See Ser.IV, "Creative Logic"
  - [Math 6 Notes], 1917 (Box 6)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. I (Box 6)
    -See Ser.IV, "Calculus of Finite Processes" Vol. I
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. II, 1942 (Box 6)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. III, 1942-1943 (Box 6)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. V, 1944 (Box 7)
    (Vol. IV is missing from this collection)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. VI, 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. VII, 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. VIII, 1946 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. IX, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. X, 1947-1948 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XI, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XII, 1948-1949 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XIII, 1949 (Box 7)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XIV, 1949-1950 (Box 8)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XV, 1950 (Box 8)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XVI, 1951 (Box 8)
  - "Theory of Finite Processes" Vol. XVII, 1951 (Box 8)
- Series V. Materials Gathered by Phyllis Post Goodman, 1955-1995; 1 box; 0.25 linear feet
  Letters, articles, and documents concerning Emil L. Post that were collected after his death. Of special interest is material concerning the republication of works by Post in Solvability, Provability, Definability: The Collected Works of Emil L. Post, edited by Martin Davis (Boston: Birhäuser, 1994) and the establishment of the Emil L. Post mathematical award at City College.
  - Barber, Sherbourne F., 1994 (Box 8)
  - Birkhäuser, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
  - Bungay, Richard, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - City College Alumnus, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
  - City College of New York, 1957-1991 (Box 8)
  - Clippings, 1954-1993, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Datamation, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Davids, Norman, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Davis, Martin, 1956-1994 (Box 8)
  - Dawson, John, 1988, 1993, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Douglas, Jesse, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Epstein, George, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Erdos, Paul, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Gleiser, Molly, 1979-1987 (Box 8)
  - Grattan-Guinness, I., 1991 (Box 8)
  - Hodges, Andrew, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, Hubert, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Kukin, Ira, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Lorch, Lee, 1990-1993 (Box 8)
  - Ozarow, Vivian, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Princeton University Press, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Rogner and Bernhard Publishing, 1972 (Box 8)
    Some in German
  - Rota, Gian-Carlo, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Springer-Verlag Publishers, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Sister Teresemarie, 1976 (Box 8)
- Series VI. Photographs, 1924, 1948; 1 box, 3 folders
  Photographs of sketches (n.d.) by Emil L. Post (the original sketches are in the possession of Phyllis Post Goodman). Also in this series is a photograph (June 1924) of Post as a young man; this photograph is one of the only formal portraits ever taken of Post. The remaining photograph is a portrait of one of Post's students.
  - Berl, Sigmund, 1948 (Box 8)
  - Post, Emil L., Jun. 1924 (Box 8)
    - Emil Post, formal portrait, June 1924., 1924 June; 1.0 Photograph(s); Bust length formal portrait of Post.
  - Photographs of Sketches by Emil L. Post, n.d. (Box 8)